Guide to the Leonard S. Marcus Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- September 2015 Acquisition, circa 1850-2015; circa 1975-2015; 110.08; (98 boxes)
  - Sound Recordings, circa 1981-2009; 22.08; (21 boxes)
    - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 72, Folder 1893)
    - Katharine Weber/Madeleine L'Engle, Goshen, 1987-06-29; 2 (Box 72, Folder 1894-1895)
    - Léna Roy, 2009-02-25; 1 (Box 72, Folder 1896)
    - Marc Simont, 2003-12-05; 1 (Box 72, Folder 1897)
      Removed from a box labeled "Artist\Author Interviews; Small Press."
    - Anne Ophelia Dowden, undated; 1 (Box 72, Folder 1898)
    - Veg Reisberg, 1989-08-01; 1 (Box 72, Folder 1899)
    - Carlos Slapin, 1989-07-26; 1 (Box 72, Folder 1900)
    - Rosh and Gardner Marin Teachers Store, 1989-08-03; 1 (Box 72, Folder 1901)
    - Interview with Stephen Von Mason, 1989-07-24; 1 (Box 72, Folder 1902)
    - Interview with Nancy Hom, 1989-07-28; 1 (Box 72, Folder 1903)
    - Enrique Chagoya, 1989-08-02; 1 (Box 72, Folder 1904)
    - Jean Vestal interview, 1995-03-09; 2 (Box 72, Folder 1905-1906)
      Removed from a box labeled "Publishing History."
    - Margaret K. McElderry on Mary Norton, 2002-11-14; 1 (Box 73, Folder 1907)
    - Refna Wilkin (Putnam), 1995-06-08; 1 (Box 73, Folder 1908)
    - Harriet Rohmer, 1989-07-21; 1 (Box 73, Folder 1909)
    - Interview with Elizabeth Riley, 1994-08-23; 2 (Box 73, Folder 1910-1911)
    - Elizabeth Riley 2nd interview, 1995-01-09; 1 (Box 73, Folder 1912)
    - Interview with Marilyn Marlow, 1994-04-22; 2 (Box 73, Folder 1913-1914)
    - Connie Epstein (on Morrow), 1995-01-05; 1 (Box 73, Folder 1915)
    - Connie Epstein, 1995-06-16; 1 (Box 73, Folder 1916)
    - Robert McClung, 1995-03-10; 1 (Box 73, Folder 1917)
    - Henrietta M. Smith, 1996-11-08; 1 (Box 73, Folder 1918)
    - Tomie dePaola, 2004-11-15; 1 (Box 73, Folder 1919)
    - Sue Alexander on SCBWI, 2007-06-14; 1 (Box 73, Folder 1920)
    - Carl Hiaasen, 2006-09-11; 1 (Box 73, Folder 1921)
      Removed from a box labeled "Don't Make Me Laugh."
    - Louis Sachar, 2006-10-11; 1 (Box 73, Folder 1922)
    - Hilary McKay, 2007-05-17; 1 (Box 73, Folder 1923)
    - Christopher Paul Curtis, 2006-10-25; 1 (Box 74, Folder 1924)
    - Judy Blume, 2007-08-21; 1 (Box 74, Folder 1925)
    - Daniel Handler, 2007-08-29; 1 (Box 74, Folder 1926)
    - Jon Scieszka, 2007-03-06; 2 (Box 74, Folder 1927-1928)
    - Anne Fine, 2006-08-11; 2 (Box 74, Folder 1929-1930)
    - Mordicai Gerstein, 2007-03-26; 1 (Box 74, Folder 1931)
      Removed from a box labeled "Pass It Down + Mordicai Gerstein for Caldecott Celebration."
    - Thacher Hurd, 2004-08-18; 1 (Box 74, Folder 1932)
    - Christopher Myers, 2004-06-04; 2 (Box 74, Folder 1933-1934)
    - Walter Dean Myers, 2004-06-10; 1 (Box 74, Folder 1935)
    - Anne + Lizzy Rockwell, 2004-08-16; 2 (Box 74, Folder 1936-1937)
    - Donald Crews + Ann Jonas, 2005-01-26; 1 (Box 74, Folder 1938)
    - Nina Crews, 2004-12-08; 1 (Box 74, Folder 1939)
    - Gloria Jean Pinkney, 2005-03-16; 1 (Box 74, Folder 1940)
    - Jerry Pinkney, 2005-01-25; 1 (Box 75, Folder 1941)
    - Brian Pinkney, 2005-02-28; 1 (Box 75, Folder 1942)
    - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 75, Folder 1943)
      Removed from a box labeled "New Ways of Telling."
    - Newbery and Caldecott Acceptance Speeches, 2009; 1 (Box 75, Folder 1944)
    - The Nation & The New School Present: A Conversation with I. F. Stone at 80, undated; 1 (Box 75, Folder 1945)
    - Eric Carle, 2009-09-01; 1 (Box 75, Folder 1946)
    - Lois Ehlert, 2009-10-12; 1 (Box 75, Folder 1947)
    - Quentin Blake, 2009-11-11 (Box 75, Folder 1948)
    - Lisbeth Zwerger, 2009-11-06; 1 (Box 75, Folder 1949)
    - Ellen Levine, 2007-03-22 (Box 75, Folder 1950)
    - Elizabeth Graves on Viking, 1996-11-20-1996-11-21; 1 (Box 75, Folder 1951)
    - Ian Schoenherr on Howard Pyle, 2007-06-28; 1 (Box 75, Folder 1952)
    - George Nicholson, 2004-12-14; 1 (Box 75, Folder 1953)
    - George Nicholson, 2006-09-21; 2 (Box 75, Folder 1954-1955)
    - Norton Juster, 2008-01-29; 1 (Box 75, Folder 1956)
    - Norton Juster, 2008-01-30; 1 (Box 75, Folder 1957)
    - Jules Feiffer, 2009-04-24; 1 (Box 76, Folder 1958)
    - Regina Hayes, 2008-02-12; 1 (Box 76, Folder 1959)
    - Kevin Henkes, 2009-11-25; 1 (Box 76, Folder 1960)
    - John Burningham, 2009-12-21; 1 (Box 76, Folder 1961)
    - Helen Oxenbury, 2009-12-21; 1 (Box 76, Folder 1962)
    - Richard Eiger, 2004-09-27-2004-09-30; 3 (Box 76, Folder 1963-1965)
    - Dan Yaccarino, 2004-10-05; 1 (Box 76, Folder 1966)
    - Betty Ren Wright, 2005-02-18; 1 (Box 76, Folder 1967)
    - Michel Duplaix, 1994-11-07; 1 (Box 76, Folder 1968)
    - George Wolfson, 2004-10-06; 1 (Box 76, Folder 1969)
    - Robin Warner, 2006-02-17; 1 (Box 76, Folder 1970)
    - Stephen Guarnaccia, 2004-11-29; 1 (Box 76, Folder 1971)
    - Alice Low, 2004-12-13; 1 (Box 76, Folder 1972)
    - Thea Feldman, 2004-11-08; 1 (Box 76, Folder 1973)
    - Tanya Koly (Rojankovsky), 2005-01-14; 1 (Box 76, Folder 1974)
    - Rich Moore, 2004-11-19; 1 (Box 77, Folder 1975)
    - Lilian Obligado, 2004-11-28; 1 (Box 77, Folder 1976)
    - Joyce Stein Golden Books (1988-1992), 2004-05-28; 1 (Box 77, Folder 1977)
    - Bud Baker, 2005-03-10; 2 (Box 77, Folder 1978-1979)
    - J. P. Leventhal + Jane Leventhal, 2004-04-20; 1 (Box 77, Folder 1980)
    - Melanie Donovan, 2004-09-10; 1 (Box 77, Folder 1981)
    - Grace Clarke, 2004-11-30; 2 (Box 77, Folder 1982-1983)
    - Rob't Baker, 2004-11-22; 1 (Box 77, Folder 1984)
    - Mel Crawford, 2005-07-14; 1 (Box 77, Folder 1985-1986)
    - Barbara Hazen on Golden Books, 2004-07-16; 1 (Box 77, Folder 1987)
    - Avi - Golden Books, 2004-05-25; 1 (Box 77, Folder 1988)
    - Harry Bliss on Mary Blair, 2004-07-13; 1 (Box 77, Folder 1989)
    - Ann M. Martin, 2004-07-16; 1 (Box 77, Folder 1990)
    - Miriam Schlein, 2004-06-25; 1 (Box 78, Folder 1991)
    - Interview with Ole Risom, 1994-11-03; 1 (Box 78, Folder 1992)
    - Greta Schreyer on Tibor Gergely, 1999-05-10; 1 (Box 78, Folder 1993)
    - Steve Santi, 2004-11-20; 1 (Box 78, Folder 1994)
    - Susan Hirschman on Sandpiper, 2004-07-05; 1 (Box 78, Folder 1995)
    - Charles Antin, 2003-10-20; 1 (Box 78, Folder 1996)
    - Marge Ternes, 2004-10-21; 1 (Box 78, Folder 1997)
    - Marc Brown, 2004-07-20; 1 (Box 78, Folder 1998)
    - Eric Suben, 2004-11-08; 1 (Box 78, Folder 1999)
    - Dik Broekman on Dutch Golden Books, 2004-06-09; 1 (Box 78, Folder 2000)
    - Bill Joyce, 2004-11-12; 1 (Box 78, Folder 2001)
    - Bob Staake, 2004-12-10; 1 (Box 78, Folder 2002)
    - Janet Chenery, 2004-09-08; 1 (Box 78, Folder 2003)
    - LSM Arts Alive from the Algonquin, 1984-12-24; 1 (Box 78, Folder 2004)
    - Interview with Eunice Blake, 1994-04-26; 1 (Box 78, Folder 2005)
    - Alvin Schwartz, undated; 1 (Box 78, Folder 2006)
    - Sendak interview with Leonard S. Marcus master copy, 1988-07-08; 1 (Box 79, Folder 2007)
    - Maurice Sendak interview with LSM 2nd copy, 1988-07-08; 1 (Box 79, Folder 2008)
    - LSM: Arts Alive from the Algonquin, 1989-12-24; 1 (Box 79, Folder 2009)
    - Margaret K. McElderry, 1993-05-11; 1 (Box 79, Folder 2010)
    - Interview with M. K. McE. [Margaret K. McElderry] completed, undated; 1 (Box 79, Folder 2011)
    - S. F. Public Library Grace Ruth + Children's Room [AMBKNCE?], 1989-08-02; 1 (Box 79, Folder 2012)
    - Maurice Sendak, 1988; 1 (Box 79, Folder 2013)
    - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 79, Folder 2014)
    - Bill Morris interview with Leonard Marcus, 1992-12-19; 1 (Box 79, Folder 2015)
    - Tamora Pierce, 2003-09-04; 1 (Box 79, Folder 2016)
    - Anno Libr. of Congress, 1987-11; 1 (Box 79, Folder 2017)
    - Mitsumasa Anno interview by Leonard S. Marcus, 1989-04-22; 2 (Box 79, Folder 2018-2019)
    - Rob't McCloskey - tape 1, undated; 1 (Box 79, Folder 2020)
    - Rob't McCloskey - additional (phone) material, 1991-04; 1 (Box 79, Folder 2021)
    - Rob't McCloskey (phone), 1991-10-04; 1 (Box 79, Folder 2022)
    - Virginia Hamilton, 1994-11-02; 1 (Box 79, Folder 2023)
    - Judith Gorog, 1998-01-13; 1 (Box 79, Folder 2024)
    - Interview with Virginia Haviland, undated; 1 (Box 80, Folder 2025)
    - Allen Say interview, 1989-08-31; 2 (Box 80, Folder 2026-2027)
    - Telephone interview with David Macaulay (in Rome), 1994-07-12; 1 (Box 80, Folder 2028)
    - Iona Opie interview Algonquin Hotel, 1988-10-21; 2 (Box 80, Folder 2029-2030)
    - Virginia Buckley, 2006-04-05; 1 (Box 80, Folder 2031)
    - James Marshall interview with L.S.M., 1989-05-24; 2 (Box 80, Folder 2032-2033)
    - Maurice Sendak, 1993-06-14; 1 (Box 80, Folder 2034)
    - Walter Wick, 2006-04-28; 2 (Box 80, Folder 2035-2036)
    - Thacher Hurd, 1996-05-07; 1 (Box 80, Folder 2037)
    - Phyllis Fogelman, 1998-09-14; 1 (Box 80, Folder 2038)
    - Interview with Doris Orgel about Ursula Nordstrom at Bank St. publications office, 1995-01-26; 1 (Box 80, Folder 2039)
    - Jon Scieszka, 1997-07-09; 1 (Box 80, Folder 2040)
    - Jon Scieszka and Lane Smith in Lane Smith's studio, 1995-05-24; 1 (Box 80, Folder 2041)
    - Dorothy Cadzow Hokanson, 1996-05-19; 1 (Box 81, Folder 2042)
    - E. L. Konigsburg, 1997-12-11; 1 (Box 81, Folder 2043)
    - Rosa Parks + Elaine Steele, 1996-07-09; 1 (Box 81, Folder 2044)
    - Marc Simont on Make Way for Ducklings, 1996-09-28; 1 (Box 81, Folder 2045)
    - Interesting phone messages, 1996; 1 (Box 81, Folder 2046)
    - Barbara Dicks on Ursula Nordstrom (2nd conversation), 1995-02-07; 1 (Box 81, Folder 2047)
    - Laurence Yep, 1997-05-21; 1 (Box 81, Folder 2048)
    - Fran Manushkin on UN [Ursula Nordstrom], 1996-10-30; 1 (Box 81, Folder 2049)
    - Russell Freedman interview, 1995-03-03; 1 (Box 81, Folder 2050)
    - Jean George, 1996-12-02; 2 (Box 81, Folder 2051-2052)
    - Chris Van Allsburg, 1996-12-12; 1 (Box 81, Folder 2053)
    - Interview with William Steig, 1994-07-14; 1 (Box 81, Folder 2054)
    - Dorothy Briley, 1996-11-13; 2 (Box 81, Folder 2055-2056)
    - Zena Sutherland on Ursula Nordstrom, 1995-06-04; 1 (Box 81, Folder 2057)
    - Margaret Rey on UN [Ursula Nordstrom], 1996-10-02; 1 (Box 81, Folder 2058)
    - Mary Rodgers, 1996 December 4; 1 (Box 82, Folder 2059, Item barcode 39002104617478)
      Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Mary Chalmers on UN [Ursula Nordstrom], 1996 November 1; 1 (Box 82, Folder 2060, Item barcode 39002104617486)
    - Unedited interview with Robert Cormier (for Listening Library), undated; 1 (Box 82, Folder 2061, Item barcode 39002104617494)
    - Johanna Hurwitz, 1995 August 28; 1 (Box 82, Folder 2062, Item barcode 39002104617502)
    - Peg Doherty on UN [Ursula Nordstrom], 1997 May 5; 1 (Box 82, Folder 2063, Item barcode 39002104617510)
    - Margaret Bloy Graham, 1996 October 10; 1 (Box 82, Folder 2064, Item barcode 39002104617528)
    - Mary Stolz, 1996 May 10; 1 (Box 82, Folder 2065, Item barcode 39002104617536)
    - Margaret Warner on UN [Ursula Nordstrom], 1996 October 14; 1 (Box 82, Folder 2066, Item barcode 39002104617544)
    - Interview with Bill Morris, 1994 October 15; 1 (Box 82, Folder 2067, Item barcode 39002104617551)
    - Ethel Heins + Paul Heins (1 of 2), 1996 April 23; 1 (Box 82, Folder 2068, Item barcode 39002104617569)
    - Ethel Heins + Paul Heins (2 of 2), 1996 April 23; 1 (Box 82, Folder 2069, Item barcode 39002104617577)
    - Interview with Susan Hirschman, 1995 March 7; 1 (Box 82, Folder 2070, Item barcode 39002104617585)
    - Susan Hirschman (1 of 2), 1995 March 10; 1 (Box 82, Folder 2071, Item barcode 39002104617593)
    - Susan Hirschman (2 of 2), 1995 March 10; 1 (Box 82, Folder 2072, Item barcode 39002104617601)
    - Judy Blume, 1998 October 30; 1 (Box 82, Folder 2073, Item barcode 39002104617619)
    - Anne Tobias on UN [Ursula Nordstrom], 1996 September 29; 1 (Box 82, Folder 2074, Item barcode 39002104617627)
    - Beverly Cleary phone interview, 1995 April 17; 1 (Box 83, Folder 2075, Item barcode 39002104617635)
    - Interview with Beverly Cleary St. Regis Hotel, 1996 July 6; 1 (Box 83, Folder 2076, Item barcode 39002104617643)
    - Charlotte Zolotow (1 of 2), 1998 October 23; 1 (Box 83, Folder 2077, Item barcode 39002104617650)
    - Charlotte Zolotow - A only (end), 1998 October 23; 1 (Box 83, Folder 2078, Item barcode 39002104617668)
    - Eric Carle, 1st part (1 of 2), 1994 July 28; 1 (Box 83, Folder 2079, Item barcode 39002104617676)
    - Eric Carle, 2nd part (original tape) (2 of 2), 1994 July 28; 1 (Box 83, Folder 2080, Item barcode 39002104617684)
    - Maurice Sendak on UN [Ursula Nordstrom], 1997 April 5; 1 (Box 83, Folder 2081, Item barcode 39002104617692)
    - Lauren Wohl (Winslow Press) on marketing, 2001 February 15; 1 (Box 83, Folder 2082, Item barcode 39002104617700)
    - Janet Schulman, 2000 January 21; 1 (Box 83, Folder 2083, Item barcode 39002104617718)
    - Esther Hautzig on marketing, 2001 February 26; 1 (Box 83, Folder 2084, Item barcode 39002104617726)
    - Suzanne Glazer, 2000 January 20; 1 (Box 83, Folder 2085, Item barcode 39002104617734)
    - Mimi Kayden, 2000 January 21; 1 (Box 83, Folder 2086, Item barcode 39002104617742)
    - Joan Robins on UN [Ursula Nordstrom], 1996 December 2; 1 (Box 83, Folder 2087, Item barcode 39002104617759)
    - Joan Robins on marketing, 2000 April 14; 1 (Box 83, Folder 2088, Item barcode 39002104617767)
    - Karla Kuskin on Ursula Nordstrom, 1995 February 8; 1 (Box 83, Folder 2089, Item barcode 39002104617775)
    - Nina Ignatowitz and Eliz. Winthrop on UN [Ursula Nordstrom], 1996 October 30; 1 (Box 83, Folder 2090, Item barcode 39002104617783)
    - Barbara Dicks on UN [Ursula Nordstrom], 1994 December 7; 1 (Box 83, Folder 2091, Item barcode 39002104617791)
    - Mary Griffith, 1995 May 9; 1 (Box 84, Folder 2092, Item barcode 39002104617809)
    - Mary Griffith, 1996 October 23; 1 (Box 84, Folder 2093, Item barcode 39002104617817)
    - Bill Morris, 2000 February 4; 1 (Box 84, Folder 2094, Item barcode 39002104617825)
    - Susan Cooper, 2003 October 1; 1 (Box 84, Folder 2095, Item barcode 39002104617833)
    - Nancy Farmer, 2003 October 23; 1 (Box 84, Folder 2096, Item barcode 39002104617841)
    - Tamora Pierce (1 of 2), 2003 September 4; 1 (Box 84, Folder 2097, Item barcode 39002104617858)
    - Tamora Pierce 2nd tape (A only) (2 of 2), 2003 September 4; 1 (Box 84, Folder 2098, Item barcode 39002104617866)
    - Terry Pratchett, 2003 August 7; 1 (Box 84, Folder 2099, Item barcode 39002104617874)
    - Diana Wynne Jones, 2002 December 6; 1 (Box 84, Folder 2100, Item barcode 39002104617882)
    - Philip Pullman, 2003 January 26; 1 (Box 84, Folder 2101, Item barcode 39002104617890)
    - Jane Yolen (1 of 2), 2002 December 20; 1 (Box 84, Folder 2102, Item barcode 39002104617908)
    - Jane Yolen (2 of 2), 2002 December 21; 1 (Box 84, Folder 2103, Item barcode 39002104617916)
    - Brian Jacques, 2003 May 5; 1 (Box 84, Folder 2104, Item barcode 39002104617924)
    - Franny Billingsley, 2002 October 7; 1 (Box 84, Folder 2105, Item barcode 39002104617932)
    - Madeleine L'Engle (1 of 2), 2002 July 1; 1 (Box 84, Folder 2106, Item barcode 39002104617940)
    - Madeleine L'Engle (2 of 2), 2002 June 1; 1 (Box 84, Folder 2107, Item barcode 39002104617957)
    - Lloyd Alexander, 2002-07-01; 2 (Box 85, Folder 2108-2109)
    - Miriam Schlein, undated; 1 (Box 85, Folder 2110)
    - Nicholasa Mohr, 1997-11-03; 1 (Box 85, Folder 2111)
    - Michael Bettman and Donna McCarthy Houghton Mifflin, 1998-02-11; 1 (Box 85, Folder 2112)
    - Bruce Brooks, 1998-07-15; 1 (Box 85, Folder 2113)
    - Lay Lee Ong on the Reys, 1998-02-05; 1 (Box 85, Folder 2114)
    - Lee Kingman, 1996-11-08; 1 (Box 85, Folder 2115)
    - Mary Cosgrave (Houghton/Pantheon), 1996-11-07; 1 (Box 85, Folder 2116)
    - William Wise on publ. history at YNE club, 1997-10-03; 1 (Box 85, Folder 2117)
    - Morell Gipson, 1997-08-26; 1 (Box 85, Folder 2118)
    - Walter Lorraine, 1997-05-19; 2 (Box 85, Folder 2119-2120)
    - Walter Lorraine, 1997-07-14; 1 (Box 85, Folder 2121)
    - William Steig, 1997-05-05; 1 (Box 85, Folder 2122)
    - Russell Freedman, 1997-03-24; 1 (Box 85, Folder 2123)
    - Joan Walsh Anglund, 1998-01-12; 1 (Box 85, Folder 2124)
    - David Wiesner, 1997-09-02; 1 (Box 86, Folder 2125)
    - Larry Untermeyer, 1998-01-08; 1 (Box 86, Folder 2126)
    - Seymour Simon, 1995-09-06; 1 (Box 86, Folder 2127)
    - Seymour Simon, 1997-12-23; 1 (Box 86, Folder 2128)
    - Chris Van Allsburg, 1996-12-12; 1 (Box 86, Folder 2129)
    - Ann M. Martin, 1997-12-16; 1 (Box 86, Folder 2130)
    - Marcia Brown, 1997-02-07; 2 (Box 86, Folder 2131-2132)
    - Tana Hoban at Greenwillow, 1997-08-26; 1 (Box 86, Folder 2133)
    - Karen Cushman, 1996-04-16; 1 (Box 86, Folder 2134)
    - Karen Cushman, 1997-10-15; 1 (Box 86, Folder 2135)
    - Michael Bettman and Donna McCarthy Houghton Mifflin, 1998-02-11; 1 (Box 86, Folder 2136)
    - Maurice Sendak, 1997-04-16; 1 (Box 86, Folder 2137)
    - Connie Epstein on Robert Bright, 1997-08-25; 1 (Box 86, Folder 2138)
    - Marcia Brown phone message, 1997-12-29; 1 (Box 86, Folder 2139)
    - Newbery, Caldecott, and Laura Ingalls Wilder Medals acceptance speeches, 2001-06; 1 (Box 86, Folder 2140)
    - Karla Kuskin, 1998-09-14; 1 (Box 86, Folder 2141)
    - Karla Kuskin, 1999-09-23; 1 (Box 87, Folder 2142)
    - Ashley Bryan, 1999-10-30; 2 (Box 87, Folder 2143-2144)
    - Jerry Pinkney, 1999-10-27; 2 (Box 87, Folder 2145-2146)
    - Rosemary Wells, 1999-10-18; 2 (Box 87, Folder 2147-2148)
    - Joanna Cole and Bruce Degen, 1999-07-01; 2 (Box 87, Folder 2149-2150)
    - Arthur Yorinks, 2000-05-09; 1 (Box 87, Folder 2151)
    - Arthur Yorinks 2nd interview, 2000-05-16; 1 (Box 87, Folder 2152)
    - Richard Egielski, 2000-08-16; 2 (Box 87, Folder 2153-2154)
    - Julius Lester, 1999-12-16; 1 (Box 87, Folder 2155)
    - Lane Smith on Baloney, 2001-01-09; 1 (Box 87, Folder 2156)
    - Jon Scieszka Baloney, 2001-01-08; 1 (Box 87, Folder 2157)
    - Jon Scieszka, 1999-08-06; 1 (Box 87, Folder 2158)
    - Linda Zuckerman on the Provensens, 2000-04-26; 1 (Box 87, Folder 2159)
    - Kevin Henkes on Wemberly Worried, 2000-04-04; 1 (Box 87, Folder 2160)
    - Helen Oxenbury, 1996-11-06; 4 (Box 88, Folder 2161-2164)
    - Charles Glinick, undated; 1 (Box 88, Folder 2165)
    - Ethel Heins + Paul Heins, 1996-04-23; 2 (Box 88, Folder 2166-2167)
    - Ethel Heins, 1996-07-20; 3 (Box 88, Folder 2168-2170)
    - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 88, Folder 2171)
    - Maggie Peirce, 1981-03-23; 1 (Box 88, Folder 2172)
    - Ann Beneduce, undated; 1 (Box 88, Folder 2173)
    - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 88, Folder 2174)
    - Bill Morris interview, 1992-12-19; 2 (Box 88, Folder 2175-2176)
    - Gratz Brown phone message praising my bio, 1992-10-31; 1 (Box 88, Folder 2177)
    - Art Songs for Children Vol 1 The Fish w/ the Deep Sea Smile + other songs of Margaret Wise Brown, undated; 1 (Box 89, Folder 2178)
    - Interview with Diane Stanley, 1996; 1 (Box 89, Folder 2179)
    - Robert McCloskey, undated; 1 (Box 89, Folder 2180)
    - Untitled, undated; 2 (Box 89, Folder 2181-2182)
    - Sandy "Yummy" Summer Songs of Margaret Wise Brown, 1994; 1 (Box 89, Folder 2183)
    - The Music of "Nimh" by Jerry Goldsmith, undated; 1 (Box 89, Folder 2184)
    - Susan Hirschman, 1995-03-10; 2 (Box 89, Folder 2185-2186)
    - New Harriet Rohmer, undated; 1 (Box 89, Folder 2187)
    - New Nancy Hom, undated; 1 (Box 89, Folder 2188)
    - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 89, Folder 2189)
    - Iona Opie, undated; 1 (Box 89, Folder 2190)
    - Foreword, undated; 1 (Box 89, Folder 2191)
    - Interview with Amy Schwartz, 1989-03-11; 2 (Box 89, Folder 2192-2193)
    - The Sendak Celebration, 1988; 1 (Box 89, Folder 2194)
    - Lee Bennett Hopkins, 1997-06-19; 1 (Box 89, Folder 2195)
    - WNYE-FM reading from A Caldecott Celebration, 1998-11-18; 1 (Box 90, Folder 2196)
    - WHYY (Philadelphia) LSM + Charlotte Zolotow talk with Marty Moss-Coane about Dear Genius, 1998-09-10; 1 (Box 90, Folder 2197)
    - Alice music - Dennis Livingston, 1999-03-21; 1 (Box 90, Folder 2198)
    - And First Came the Book: A History of Children's Publishing & Bookselling, ABA Annual Meeting, undated; 1 (Box 90, Folder 2199)
    - Margaret Wise Brown Young People's Records, undated; 1 (Box 90, Folder 2200)
    - Lane Smith and Molly Leach, 2000-02-23; 1 (Box 90, Folder 2201)
    - Luci Shaw, 2009-08-14; 1 (Box 90, Folder 2202)
    - Charlotte Jones, 2009-02-11; 1 (Box 90, Folder 2203)
- August 2016 Acquisition, circa 1988-2015; 3.67; (4 boxes)
  Gift of Leonard S. Marcus (Yale 1972), 2016.
  Organized into two series: I. Parenting Magazine, 1989-1995. II. Other Short Works and Events, 1988-2015.
  - Parenting Magazine, 1989-1995; 2.17; (2 boxes)
    Drafts, notes, and correspondence concerning Marcus's tenure as contributing editor and children's literature reviewer at Parenting magazine.
    - 1989 columns (Box 98, Folder 2320-2325)
    - Reading-Magic Awards, 1989 (Box 98, Folder 2326-2327)
    - 1990 columns (Box 98, Folder 2328-2338)
    - ABA Las Vegas, 1990 (Box 98, Folder 2339)
    - Reading-Magic Awards, 1990 (Box 98, Folder 2340-2341)
    - 1991 columns (Box 98, Folder 2342-2356)
    - ABA New York, 1991 (Box 98, Folder 2357)
    - Reading-Magic Awards, 1991 (Box 98, Folder 2358-2359)
    - 1992 columns (Box 98, Folder 2360-2366)
    - 1992 columns (Box 99, Folder 2367-2371)
    - ABA Anaheim, 1992 (Box 99, Folder 2372)
    - Reading-Magic Awards, 1992 (Box 99, Folder 2373-2374)
    - 1993 columns (Box 99, Folder 2375-2387)
    - ABA Miami, 1993 (Box 99, Folder 2388)
    - Reading-Magic Awards, 1993 (Box 99, Folder 2389-2390)
    - 1994 columns (Box 99, Folder 2391-2403)
    - ABA Los Angeles, 1994 (Box 99, Folder 2404)
    - Reading-Magic Awards, 1994 (Box 99, Folder 2405-2406)
    - 1995 columns (Box 100, Folder 2407-2419)
    - ABA Chicago, 1995 (Box 100, Folder 2420)
    - Reading-Magic Awards, 1995 (Box 100, Folder 2421-2422)
  - Other Short Works and Events, 1988-2015; 1.5; (2 boxes)
    - PEN New England, 1998 (Box 100, Folder 2423)
    - mySimon.com reviews, 2001 (Box 100, Folder 2424-2431)
    - PEN/Norma Klein Award nominations, 1999 (Box 100, Folder 2432)
    - Conferences, announcements, and publishers' releases, 1993-2014 (Box 100, Folder 2433)
    - Loose Leaf Book Company, 2001-2002 (Box 100, Folder 2434)
    - Hollins College, 1997-07-23 (Box 100, Folder 2435)
    - Bookradio.com, 2000 (Box 100, Folder 2436)
    - NCTE talk, 1999 (Box 100, Folder 2437)
    - Bank Street new perspectives retreat, 2001 (Box 100, Folder 2438)
    - Cricket anniversary program, 2003-10-16 (Box 100, Folder 2439)
    - USBBY Hans Christian Andersen committee, 1988 (Box 100, Folder 2440)
    - CBC Features children's book publishing issue, 2001 (Box 100, Folder 2441)
    - Nassau Public Library talk, 1993-11-01 (Box 100, Folder 2442)
    - William B. Ward Elementary School talk, 1992-03-03 (Box 100, Folder 2443)
    - "Modern Books for Modern Children" talk, Donnell Central Children's Room, NYPL, 1993-04-20 (Box 100, Folder 2444)
    - National Conference on Liberal Arts School of Visual Arts, 1989-11 (Box 100, Folder 2445)
    - New York is Kids Book Country, 2012-04-26 (Box 100, Folder 2446)
    - The Park School, 1996-10-09 (Box 100, Folder 2447)
    - SCBWI Metro New York, 2000-11-14 (Box 100, Folder 2448)
    - Vassar College Margaret Wise Brown exhibition, 1992-06 (Box 100, Folder 2449)
    - Connecticut Children's Book Fair, 1992-05-03 (Box 100, Folder 2450)
    - ALA/CBC program, "The Story Behind the Poem", 2001 (Box 100, Folder 2451)
    - Bard College Swedish toy exhibition, 2015 (Box 100, Folder 2452)
    - Katonah Museum of Art, 2007-09-30 (Box 100, Folder 2453)
    - Bank Street talk, 2014-11-14 (Box 100, Folder 2454)
    - Provo, Utah Public Library, 2015-07 (Box 100, Folder 2455)
    - Norman Rockwell Museum, 2015-07-23 (Box 100, Folder 2456)